<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>elcuervo</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on elcuervo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom is optional</title>
      <link>/blog/freedom-is-optional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/freedom-is-optional/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have the tendency to balance my full nerd side with nature. Camping really far
away with the bare minimum. I like to go off the grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so many years ago we lived without checking on Foursquare, without telling
what we were doing on Twitter or who is our partner on Facebook. We even lived
without sms. Only with spare change in our pockets and ideas in our minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital revolution came and we went from connecting to the internet some
times of the day, to struggle to disconnect some times of the day.
We now are premanently on-the-grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was born in a third world country where access to information was limited
having nowdays the ability to be constantly connected felt awesome. All the information of
mankind in one place. I could learn anything, free, I just needed to spend some
time and I could learn the most complex networking papers or read the most touching
poems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other problems araised, we started to get confused with the amount of
communication we had&amp;hellip; started to think that it was actual connection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/70534716&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34;
frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen
allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But like with everything there&amp;rsquo;s a trade off. Not everyone looked at the
internet as an information source, a lot looked at it as an oportuniy but a
handful of them started this ancient trend of privacy invasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now know that a lot of goverments are eager to know everything we do.
Obviously this is not limited to goverments but also companies, from small ones
to mega corporations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/82666985&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34;
frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen
allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does not matter if you use Windows, Linux or OSX you are on the grid and you
know it. There&amp;rsquo;s no &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; freedom out there. Because it&amp;rsquo;s not about the
software you use, it&amp;rsquo;s how you use it and in our specific case how you build it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security bugs (including, but not limited to, backdoors) exist in a ton of software and even in
hardware. The curiosity to know and the interest to do so is a powerful hand
that does not care about software or hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free of choice, free of thought, free of discrimination, of persecution. I do
not accept the &lt;strong&gt;one true way of living&lt;/strong&gt; ideals.
able to run it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started coding PHP, but I&amp;rsquo;m no PHP dev. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Python, but I&amp;rsquo;m no
Python dev. Most of my career is around Ruby, but I&amp;rsquo;m no Ruby dev.
I&amp;rsquo;m a developer. I love to code anything, in any language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;m not tied to any OS, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this in OSX but I own several machines
with several OSs. I enjoy being a poweruser in any system, as well as other
people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My war today is against people who want to tell me how to think, how to feel.
Against people who wants to tag me and use me in a statistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My war today is against the ones who think their way is the only way, because
once there was only one acceptable gender, one acceptable color, one
acceptable faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-rock-in-a-pond:ec7f2f36e548c1f1f32c9e72d1aa72b3&#34;&gt;A rock in a pond&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For to be free is not merely to cast off one&amp;rsquo;s chains, but to live in a way
that respects and enhances the freedom of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nelson Mandela&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes enough is enough. Sometimes a part of you can&amp;rsquo;t take things anymore.
Sometimes you are not going to wait for someone to fix things. Sometimes it has
to be you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a programmer is by far the most important thing that I achieved in my
life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async class=&#34;speakerdeck-embed&#34; data-id=&#34;095e73303aab0131eddb6ef1f34b6106&#34; data-ratio=&#34;1.33333333333333&#34; src=&#34;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/90438418?byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=97ceec&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things inspire you to go the extra mile. Some things trigger that part of
you that was asleep. Some things happen all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;disobey:ec7f2f36e548c1f1f32c9e72d1aa72b3&#34;&gt;Disobey&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And our topic is topsy-turvy: civil disobedience. As soon as you say the topic
is civil disobedience, you are saying our problem is civil disobedience. That
is not our problem&amp;hellip;. Our problem is civil obedience. Our problem is the
numbers of people all over the world who have obeyed the dictates of the
leaders of their government and have gone to war, and millions have been
killed because of this obedience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Howard Zinn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These words made me realize something. This is not the first time this happened,
some things in our world are repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These acts of defiance are a vestige of the vox populi, now vacant, vanished. But
that is not a barrier to battle the brutality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anarchy&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;comes from the ancient Greek ἀναρχία, anarchia, from
ἀν an, &amp;ldquo;not, without&amp;rdquo; + ἀρχός arkhos, &amp;ldquo;ruler&amp;rdquo;, meaning &amp;ldquo;absence of a ruler&amp;rdquo;,
&amp;ldquo;without rulers&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anarchy is not only a political view, but also a philosofical one.
Anarchy is often tied with violence, with hate.
I&amp;rsquo;m seeing a world of violence, with hate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have the one true way of living. I want to dedicate my life to
give everyone the chance to choose, to love, to hate to be free in all extent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be in the wrong path&amp;hellip; but this time, this time I choosed this path and
I&amp;rsquo;m going to defend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programmers, designers, journalists, creators. That skill to make something from
nothingness, that skill inherent in every person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a rebel, an inconformist it&amp;rsquo;s also part of everyone.
And at the end freedom, that gift with our first breath, is not optional. It&amp;rsquo;s
not a law, a right&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a condition. A living being condition that can&amp;rsquo;t be
removed, can&amp;rsquo;t be bought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are the victims of our own fears, of our own demons, of our own humanity.
Today&amp;hellip; today is the day we fight back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The zen way</title>
      <link>/blog/the-zen-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-zen-way/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I wonder about my choices. I wonder about my look, the things I say,
the reactions I trigger on people. But since a long time I do not wonder about
one thing: my code choices and how they triggered a life choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some things that change the way you think. I tend to prefer simple
approaches to things, specially complex problems. I don&amp;rsquo;t see right complex
solutions only because the problem looks complex itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is a brief story on my journey from a complex point of view &lt;strong&gt;ONLY&lt;/strong&gt; in code
to a minimal view not only in code but also in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;allow-yourself-to-be-inspired:914233283eb0f8905d54c17cc4e38b56&#34;&gt;Allow yourself to be inspired&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything should be made as simple as possible, but not simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Einstein&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My way started some years ago after struggling with Rails and don&amp;rsquo;t finding
peace with it. I was spending more time fighting with layers and layers of code
that my boss promised me will make my life easier. It was not, I was angry on
the lack of understanding I had. I was angry at me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code you write it&amp;rsquo;s nothing more than a reflection of who you are, code it&amp;rsquo;s
a part of you. That&amp;rsquo;s why we need creativity, that&amp;rsquo;s why we burnout because when
that reflection fades, a part of us does the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was promised a world of awesomeness after I started coding with Rails. I fell
in love with Ruby when I started but some time working only with Rails&amp;hellip; well I
derailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt empty, that code was not me. And that was poisonous for me. I do not have
a work-life and a life in another place. This is my life&amp;hellip; work and OSS are
parts that define me so doing something annoying breaks my soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it happened. We were visited by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/soveran&#34;&gt;soveran&lt;/a&gt;
and he introduced us his latest project: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/soveran/cuba&#34;&gt;Cuba&lt;/a&gt;
at that point based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chneukirchen/rum&#34;&gt;Rum&lt;/a&gt;, maybe you
recognize the name of the author because he wrote
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rack/rack&#34;&gt;Rack&lt;/a&gt;. The project later evolved to a standalone
lib that didn&amp;rsquo;t use Rum at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long story short I viewed a world beyond the cluttered Rails philosophy. And I
saw that another lifestyle was possible, that my demands of a simpler work-style
could be achievable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was still struggling with Rails in my work. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand why someone
could see this as &amp;ldquo;fast development&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;class ETooMuchMagic &amp;lt; ApplicationController
  def index
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&#34;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; that was the first
thing I saw as simple.
Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, Sinatra is really pretty&amp;hellip; but still&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s magic
there. And I&amp;rsquo;m a person of science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;get &amp;quot;/magic&amp;quot; do
  erb :index
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I started to use Cuba all the time, in every scenario just for the
love of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;on &amp;quot;magic&amp;quot; do
  res.write &amp;quot;Roll your own&amp;quot;
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously the place I worked wasn&amp;rsquo;t really happy about that choice and I only
were &amp;ldquo;allowed&amp;rdquo; to use Cuba once in a client project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I got the point of so much minimalism&amp;hellip; I started seeing beyond the
code itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were something else, I&amp;rsquo;ve started trying to understandd it&amp;hellip; every piece of
code. The concept of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Middleware&#34;&gt;Middlewares&lt;/a&gt;
started to appear, pattern matching,
caching, HTTP codes, headers&amp;hellip; lot of stuff that was hidden in the magic for
my &amp;ldquo;protection&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;Cuba.use Cuba::Render
Cuba.use Middleware::Of::Your::Choice

Cuba.define do
  on root do
    res.write view(&amp;quot;home&amp;quot;)
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was forced to learn&amp;hellip; to understand, and that&amp;rsquo;s the difference. I was really
understanding every part of the app. When things go wrong I could easily
identify it and fix it&amp;hellip; I was extremelly happy knowing that the app was truly
a part of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;build-your-own-tools:914233283eb0f8905d54c17cc4e38b56&#34;&gt;Build your own tools&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simplicity is the final achievement. After one has played a vast quantity of
notes and more notes, it is simplicity that emerges as the crowning reward of
art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frederic Chopin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start to understand how things work you fall in love of simplicity. Not
as a hacky way on doing stuff but as a form of art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first gem I wrote was &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elcuervo/ohm-find_by&#34;&gt;Ohm find_by&lt;/a&gt;
just because I wanted to have some of the stuff made Rails easy while using
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/soveran/ohm&#34;&gt;Ohm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it happened. I needed something. But every thing I found had a lot of
code impossible to read or understand. I needed a testing framework for the
browser&amp;hellip; just a simple &lt;code&gt;assert&lt;/code&gt;. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find nothing.
That&amp;rsquo;s how &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elcuervo/gerbil&#34;&gt;Gerbil&lt;/a&gt; was born&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;scenario(&amp;quot;This is my scenario&amp;quot;, {
  &amp;quot;setup&amp;quot;:  function()  { /* When scenario starts */ },
  &amp;quot;before&amp;quot;: function()  { /* Before every test */ },
  &amp;quot;after&amp;quot;:  function()  { /* After every test */ },
  &amp;quot;cleanup&amp;quot;: function() { /* When the scenario ends */ },

  &amp;quot;MagicThing should have a length&amp;quot;: function(g) {
    this.someThing.add(1);
    g.assertEqual(this.someThing.length, 1);
  },

  &amp;quot;MagicThing should be valid&amp;quot;: function(g) {
    g.assert(this.someThing.valid);
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it worked&amp;hellip; it is crappy code but it worked. Simple, straightforward and
readable since it&amp;rsquo;s only one file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was all that I needed to test &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elcuervo/lodis&#34;&gt;Lodis&lt;/a&gt;
another project just for fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the snowball effect&amp;hellip; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop. Open source became part of me.
A really important part. The things I learned from all the incredible people out
there is just amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same inspiration &amp;ldquo;forced&amp;rdquo; me to try to share my thoughts. My ideas.
And with minimalism in mind I gave this talk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/44025029&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;283&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;you-won-t-be-alone:914233283eb0f8905d54c17cc4e38b56&#34;&gt;You won&amp;rsquo;t be alone&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfection is achieved, not when there is nothing more to add, but when there
is nothing left to take away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antoine de Saint-Exupe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was surprised with this new world, minimal code and joyful solutions. But what
really surprised me was the world I joined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of brilliant people are out there ready to show you their ways. You can be
blown away with people like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cyx&#34;&gt;cyx&lt;/a&gt; and his amazing
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cyx/dep&#34;&gt;dep&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/inkel&#34;&gt;inkel&lt;/a&gt; and his
plain simple daemon lib &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/inkel/fallen&#34;&gt;Fallen&lt;/a&gt;, or laugh
with the brilliance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tonchis/gst&#34;&gt;gst&lt;/a&gt; from the huggable
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tonchis&#34;&gt;tonchis&lt;/a&gt;, or choose
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lucasefe/gn&#34;&gt;gn&lt;/a&gt; the simple generator from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lucasefe&#34;&gt;lucasefe&lt;/a&gt; or even see your closest friend release
outstanding projects like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pote&#34;&gt;pote&lt;/a&gt; Go dependency manager
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pote/gpm&#34;&gt;gpm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But nothing prepares you to meet great people in person. You could read every
piece of code, understand every method but you can find a special light when you
hug them, share a beer, a gist, an informal talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are not alone, there&amp;rsquo;s another way to see the world. A way that probably
it&amp;rsquo;s not going to give the top notch job of your Rails shop&amp;hellip; but it&amp;rsquo;s going to
give you an amount of knowledge that can help you overcome every rock in the
way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;apply-it-to-your-life:914233283eb0f8905d54c17cc4e38b56&#34;&gt;Apply it to your life&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have nothing in your houses that you do not know to be useful, or believe to
be beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;William Morris&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes in life you had to make choices. Choices that go in the opposite
direction that your brain tells you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year ago I had a ticket for &lt;a href=&#34;http://eurucamp.org&#34;&gt;Eurucamp&lt;/a&gt;, a ticket that
was around 70EUR if I recall correctly. And I give it away&amp;hellip; I really needed
the money but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I had an opportunity, the opportunity to invest my money in hope. Hope in
someone I didn&amp;rsquo;t know. Hope that having less is going to give me more in the
future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tweeted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/eurucamp&#34;&gt;@eurucamp&lt;/a&gt; telling them that I had a
ticket to give away for a good reason. Few moments after that
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sheley&#34;&gt;@sheley&lt;/a&gt; answered me telling me that she wanted to
switch careers and wanted to go to Eurucamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave her the ticket with some minor conditions, that happened one year ago. A
Few weeks ago she told me that she now have her first job as a developer.
I&amp;rsquo;m extremely proud of her and I&amp;rsquo;m eager to know what&amp;rsquo;s next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She wrote her journey in &lt;a href=&#34;http://ihatehandshakes.com/blog/2014/it-takes-a-village-to-make-a-programmer/&#34;&gt;her blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; Currently I see the blog down, but you can see a &lt;a href=&#34;http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:ihatehandshakes.com/blog/2014/it-takes-a-village-to-make-a-programmer/&#34;&gt;cached
version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started applying that minimalism to my life and my work habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have services on login, I have this in my &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; and this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elcuervo/dotfiles/blob/master/zsh/zsh/tools.sh&#34;&gt;tool&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;load_services() {
  if [ -f &amp;quot;.services&amp;quot; ]; then start_services; fi;
}

chpwd() {
  load_services
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this journey you find stuff&amp;hellip; stuff that changes you. You inspire and get
inspired by people but also by the things around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this attempt to become a minimalist, in code and life I found something else.
I found the inspiration and the transpiration to break my limits, my rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you find a way you want to share it as well and that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing
in my talks but one talk is different one talk is the echo of my thoughts it had
my rage and my love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My talk in &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubyconfargentina.org&#34;&gt;Ruby Conf Argentina&lt;/a&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s a sum of my
beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every action there&amp;rsquo;s a reaction. The great people who inspired me gave me
the tools to became who am I. And that&amp;rsquo;s why I know this talk it&amp;rsquo;s just the echo
of great people. The ones who fought clutter, noise and oppression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async class=&#34;speakerdeck-embed&#34; data-id=&#34;095e73303aab0131eddb6ef1f34b6106&#34; data-ratio=&#34;1.33333333333333&#34; src=&#34;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs a war and an ideal to stand upon. And thanks to my friends I
found mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;live-and-let-die:914233283eb0f8905d54c17cc4e38b56&#34;&gt;Live and let die&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret of happiness, you see, is not found in seeking more, but in
developing the capacity to enjoy less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Socrates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my way, the path I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen. Most of the things you read here will only
apply to me but maybe and just maybe can inspire you to do something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to be able to inspire someone as others inspire me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t see my life without code, I can&amp;rsquo;t see my code without minimalism
therefore I can&amp;rsquo;t see my life without minimalism. It&amp;rsquo;s one thing, and a thing
that pushes me forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losing can be hard and unnatural. Getting rid of layers and layers in life can
become a struggle since we are raised in a world were you are measured based on
what you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s your life and your code, you have the power to choose your way and share it
if you want but remember , it&amp;rsquo;s your way, your life and at the end the race it&amp;rsquo;s
only against yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gost</title>
      <link>/blog/gost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of fantastic projects out there. One of them being
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goworker.org/&#34;&gt;goworker&lt;/a&gt; which is a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/defunkt/resque&#34;&gt;Resque&lt;/a&gt; compatible project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes you want something simpler. And as usual is easy to get that kind
of simplicity of the right Ruby projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time the inspiration comes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/soveran/ost&#34;&gt;Ost&lt;/a&gt;. This
is a lightweight lib to enqueue jobs to be executed in workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push a job you simply do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;Ost[:videos_to_process].push(@video.id)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to do something with it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;require &amp;quot;ost&amp;quot;

Ost[:videos_to_process].each do |id|
  # Do something with it!
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired bit its simplicity I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elcuervo/gost&#34;&gt;Gost&lt;/a&gt; a
Go package that allows you to start Ost compatible queues or use it as it own
thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;import &amp;quot;github.com/elcuervo/gost&amp;quot;

// ...

gost := gost.Connect(&amp;quot;:6379&amp;quot;)
gost.Push(&amp;quot;my_jobs&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;id_to_be_procesed&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it, the &lt;code&gt;id_to_be_procesed&lt;/code&gt; id is pushed to the &lt;code&gt;my_jobs&lt;/code&gt; queue ready
for the next worker to fetch it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;gost.Each(&amp;quot;my_jobs&amp;quot;, func(id string) bool {
  if(doesSomethingWithTheId(id)) {
    // Everything is ok
    return true
  } else {
    // If the fn returns false the
    // items is kept in the backup key
    return false
  }
})
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do more things like knowing how many items are to be executed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;gost.Items(&amp;quot;my_jobs&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or stoping the worker. Useful if you want to make your worker gracefully exit
given a system signal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;gost.Stop()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitcher</title>
      <link>/blog/twitcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/twitcher/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One of the beautiful things about Open Source it&amp;rsquo;s just to build something you
want ONLY because you want it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has a mentor or at least references, people you admire. On top of my
list are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/soveran&#34;&gt;soveran&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cyx&#34;&gt;cyx&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/inkel&#34;&gt;inkel&lt;/a&gt; and thanks to their guidance I&amp;rsquo;m a big
advocate of small libraries with clear responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind I made &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elcuervo/twitcher&#34;&gt;Twitcher&lt;/a&gt; wich
is basically a wrapper on top of the &lt;code&gt;Go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;time.NewTicker&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-it-work:1f08020ee62a231837cdb8458bf1e6e2&#34;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;twitcher := twitcher.NewTwitcher(time.Second * 30)
twitcher.Do(func() {
  println(&amp;quot;I&#39;m going to be executed every 30 seconds&amp;quot;)
})
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s just slightly different from using &lt;code&gt;Go&lt;/code&gt; stdlib &lt;code&gt;Ticker&lt;/code&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, this would be the example using it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;t := time.NewTicker(time.Second * 30)
go func() {
  for {
    &amp;lt;-t.C
    println(&amp;quot;I&#39;m going to be executed every 30 seconds&amp;quot;)
  }
}()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the catch comes when you want to update the &amp;ldquo;ticking&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t just modify the channel you need to wrap it in something and that&amp;rsquo;s
what Twitcher does. Let&amp;rsquo;s you easily modify the reference to the channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for that reason &lt;code&gt;Twitcher&lt;/code&gt; exists. To have an &lt;code&gt;Update&lt;/code&gt; and an easy way to
execute a function on each tick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;twitcher.Update(time.Second * 5)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will change the execution time of the function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you can &lt;code&gt;Stop&lt;/code&gt; the function just by calling it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;twitcher.Stop()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you want to access the channel to do your own stuff. And you can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;for {
  &amp;lt;-twitcher.C
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you find this helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kawarau</title>
      <link>/travels/kawarau-jump/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/travels/kawarau-jump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/travels/kawarau/k01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/travels/kawarau/k02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/travels/kawarau/k03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/travels/kawarau/k04.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/travels/kawarau/k05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/travels/kawarau/k06.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;854&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x9OF5XyQ4gQ&#34;
frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legends don&#39;t die</title>
      <link>/blog/legends-dont-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/legends-dont-die/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is a sad sad day. Today is the day that Jim Weirich died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing this is my way of handling the grief:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was that way. A long time before the gender wars, even before concurrency
debate there was this man. He saw in you stuff that you couldn&amp;rsquo;t find in the
mirror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was that way. Even in your darkest time he would see light in you. Having
an intellect more developed than any other person he will just shine with his
laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was that way. After being part of the internet for so long he always wanted
to give everyone a chance, you could always learn something from him&amp;hellip; from
yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s hard for you to understand. I know that everyone around you rants
and criticize everything you say. I know that people around you enjoy trying
to look better than you, belive me&amp;hellip; I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the world was different back then, it&amp;rsquo;s the same planet but a
lot changed. People focus on their differences now, they look for every single
detail that makes them different trying to ignore the absurd amount of things
that makes all of us the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was not that way. He had the curiosity of a child, their innocence, their
love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was not that way. He shared every single thing he knew, not for profit, for
fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was not that way. He smiled and give you his opinion with respect, not for
fame, but for a greater good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s hard for you to understand how hard is the pain to see a world
without him. But I know that you can be as amazing as he was because now you
have a part of him. Now you know who he was and how important is to be a good
person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are not going to meet the man, you will listen to his legend. And legends
don&amp;rsquo;t die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are standing on the shoulders of a kind giant&amp;hellip; now aim higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people want to live forever but only a few will.
Jim is one of those people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time someone will run &lt;code&gt;rake&lt;/code&gt; or just think about testing he will be there.
Inspiring all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the blogpost written today talk about his kindness and about the way he made
everyone he touched a better person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m lucky enough to have shared some time with him, working, learning, laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you kind giant, now sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/4726642&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;visual=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>